

ORPAA LUBEM IT SUPPORT OFFICER

Contact Details orpaastephen@gmail.com +2347052532663

Contact Address:

Plot 208, Hakimi Aliyu Layout, Mokwa, Niger State, 913104 Nationality:

Nigeria

Date of Birth:

18th October, 199*

LinksPortfolioLinkedInGithubTwitter

> Skills



Windows Server 2022



Linux

Flutter + Dart

UI (Vue.js+HTML+CSS+JS)

MS Office

Fast Learner

Adaptability

★★★★ Communication Skills

Profile

I am IT Officer with close-on a decade accumulated practical experience in analyzing and problem-solving technical issues with workable solutions in Cyber Security, System Admin, Network Support and IT Support roles with top Nigeria tertiary institution and global leading agro-allied company. I am highly energetic and dedicated IT officer with experience in assisting colleagues, Forward-thinking and team-oriented with a proven history of thinking strategically and initiating action to meet deadlines. Recognized by management and colleagues as an individual who takes on challenges and new responsibilities, and gets things done right. I build Mobile Apps using Flutter for fun.

Employment History

IT Officer (Full-Time) at Flour Mills of Nigerian (Golden Sugar Company, Sunti)

Date: January, 2023 - Present

Key Responsibility:

- As an IT Officer I was involve providing technical support related to both hardware, software and Human-ware.
- Provide remote support while carrying out quarterly system backup using Veeam
- Implement Cisco Security firewall on the Network using Fortinet 81E
- Monitoring Network using Meraki dashboard and Ensuring smooth flow of internet on company Switches and Access points (Cisco Routers)
- Perform network maintenance and system upgrades including service packs, patches, hotfixes and security configurations
- LAN support and maintenance
- Monitor performance and ensure system availability and reliability
- Provide Level-2/3 support and troubleshooting to resolve issues
- Report and resolve network down times with full speed
- Responsible for update/implementation of system security patch, enforcing OS upgrade and Staff training for new UI usage
- Help to ensure the safe and efficient running of a company's IT gadgets and provide user technical support/assistance.
- Ensured company's computer network is always running smoothly, efficiently and up-todate
- Responsible for writing reports, training staff on new technologies, and developing/implement contingency plans in case of network failure.
- Performed installations and configuring of new computer PC on FMN Domain and Networks
- Setting up Peripherals, Maintaining and repairing them.
- Liaise with vendors and other IT personnel for problem resolution
- Work within the established configuration and change management policies to ensure awareness, approval and success of changes made to the network infrastructure
- Select and implement security tools, policies, and procedures in conjunction with the company's security team.
- Investigating, diagnosing and resolve all network problems
- Troubleshooting, maintenance and replacement of computer hardware.
- Communicating and negotiating with users, specialists, other staff and suppliers.
- Troubleshooting and repair of software issues.

Date: March, 2012 - September, 2013

- Maintaining software application on LAN i.e. MFG Pro, Microsoft Outlook, SAP.
- Maintenance of networks and peripheral equipment

↓ User Support (Intern) at Federal University of Agriculture, Makurdi

Key Responsibility

- Assist over 3,000 students in the creation of student's Username and password to grant them access to ICT wireless facility
- Enable Staff to collate student data consumption information from the school admin network server.
- Team leader of IT student during the PC upgrade from wired to wireless card to enable



Travelling Writing Functional Codes

Languages

English - Professional

Hebrew - Basic Espanol - Basic Hausa - Fluent

Education

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc)
 in Computer Science from
 Federal University of
 Agriculture, Makurdi (now
 Joseph Sarwuan Tarka
 University)

Date: August, 2023

> National Diploma from The Federal Polytechnic, Bida Date: September, 2014

SSCE from Government
 Day Seconder School, Kpege,
 Mokwa

Date: July, 2009

> FSLC from Abi Nursery and Primary School, Badariya

Date: August, 2003

References

 ...will be available on request.

♣ Junior Android Developer (Intern) at Build Space Hub

Date: March, 2021 - December, 2022

Key Responsibility

- Develop app using Flutter & Dart
- Implement Apps Using Firebase, Google Cloud and Google authentication
- Used Retrofit for handling RESTful AP calls
- Used Mobile-ads and Facebook

♣ Computer Instructor (Full Time) at Rock Computer Cyber Café

Date: March, 2018 - March, 2021

Key Responsibility

- Install and Administrate Mikrotic software over the wireless network
- Configure/Setup wireless network firewall
- Used e-Platform (Remita, Quickteller, Others) for payment

♣ Computer Operator (Full Time) at Bekesoft InfoSys and DataTech

Date: November, 2009 - August, 2011

Key Responsibility

- Computer System Unit Assembly and Installation
- DBMS Application End-User
- MS-Office Application End-User
- Corel-Draw & CS-4 End-User

Store Keeper (Full Time) at Saro Agro Science Company

Date: May, 2015 - March, 2018

Key Responsibility

- Monitor and ensure proper In-Flow and Out-Flow of Stocks ensure daily stock balancing with sales reps.
- Implemented new customer service strategies successfully, increasing customer satisfaction by 9% in 11 months.
- Calculate total payments received during a time period, and reconcile this with total sales.
- Used computerized systems that involve distributing and accounting for funds
- Operate POS cash register, handling 20 transactions on average daily
- Calculate total payments received during a time period, and reconcile this with total sales
- Responsible for Quarterly Stock count and balancing of SKUs

♣ Security Personnel (Full Time) at Ashaka Security Company (ASCO)

Date: March, 2020 - December, 2020

Key Responsibility

Maintain total alertness and Secure all company properties within allocated perimeter

> Professional Certs

 Windows Server 2022 (Implementing Group Policy/DHCP&DNS/Install & Configure Active Directory)

Date: March, 2024

• IT and Cyber Security Essentials

Date: January, 2024

• Mobile-Web Specialist at Google Developers

Date: July, 2021

 Fundamental of Android & iOS App using Flutter & Dart at London App Brewery + Google Developers

Date: April, 2020

• CCNA Security at Network Bull, India

Date: September, 2020

• CCNA Networking (Routing & Switching) at Network Bull, India
Date: July, 2014

Diploma in Computer Operations at Bidapoly Consult

Date: August, 2012